<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML -->
<!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 -->
<TaggedPDF-doc>
<?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?>
<?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c041 52.342996, 2008/05/07-20:48:00        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreateDate>2010-09-26T21:54:42-05:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2010-09-26T21:54:42-05:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>iText 5.0.4 (c) 1T3XT BVBA</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?>
<?xpacket end='r'?>

<chapter>
<title>chapter I 2 LOOMINGS</title>

<para>Call me Ishmael. Some years ago--never mind how longprecisely --having little or no money in my purse, and nothingparticular to interest me on shore, I thought I would sail about alittle and see the watery part of the world. It is a way I have ofdriving off the spleen, and regulating the circulation. Whenever Ifind myself growing grim about the mouth; whenever it is a damp,drizzly November in my soul; whenever I find myself involuntarilypausing before coffin warehouses, and bringing up the rear ofevery funeral I meet; and especially whenever my hypos get suchan upper hand of me, that it requires a strong moral principle toprevent me from deliberately stepping into the street, andmethodically knocking people's hats off--then, I account it hightime to get to sea as soon as I can.</para>

<para>This is my substitute for pistol and ball. With a philosophicalflourish Cato throws himself upon his sword; I quietly take to theship. There is nothing surprising in this. If they but knew it, almostall men in their degree, some time or other, cherish very nearlythe same feelings towards the ocean with me. There now is yourinsular city of the Manhattoes, belted round by wharves as Indianisles by coral reefs--commerce surrounds it with her surf.</para>

<para>Right and left, the streets take you waterward. Its extreme down-town is the battery, where that noble mole is washed by waves,and cooled by breezes, which a few hours previous were out ofsight of land. Look at the crowds of water-gazers there.Circumambulate the city of a dreamy Sabbath afternoon. Go fromCorlears Hook to Coenties Slip, and from thence, by Whitehallnorthward. What do you see?--Posted like silent sentinels allaround the town, stand thousands upon thousands of mortal menfixed in ocean reveries. Some leaning against the spiles; someseated upon the pier-heads; some looking over the bulwarksglasses of ships from China; some high aloft in the rigging, as ifstriving to get a still better seaward peep. But these are alllandsmen; of week days pent up in lath and plaster--tied tocounters, nailed to benches, clinched to desks. How then is this?Are the green fields gone? What do they here? But look! herecome more crowds, pacing straight for the water, and seeminglybound for a dive. Strange! Nothing will content them but theextremest limit of the land; loitering under the shady lee of yonderwarehouses will not suffice. No. They must get just as nigh thewater as they possibly can without falling in. And there theystand--miles of them--leagues. Inlanders all, they come fromlanes and alleys, streets and avenues, --north, east, south, andwest. Yet here they all unite. Tell me, does the magnetic virtue ofthe needles of the compasses of all those ships attract themthither? Once more. Say, you are in the country; in some highland of lakes. Take almost any path you please, and ten to one itcarries you down in a dale, and leaves you there by a pool in thestream. There is magic in it. Let the most absent-minded of menbe plunged in his deepest reveries--stand that man on his legs,set his feet a-going, and he will infallibly lead you to water, ifwater there be in all that region. Should you ever be athirst in thegreat American desert, try this experiment, if your caravanhappen to be supplied with a metaphysical professor. Yes, asevery one knows, meditation and water are wedded for ever.</para>
</chapter>
</TaggedPDF-doc>
