<Sect><Heading#201>University of Illinois at Urbana Champaign 
Academic Staff  
2010-2011 Report of Non-University Activities (RNUA) 
Disclosure and Request for Prior Approval </Heading#201>
<Normal> </Normal>
<DOUBLE#20SPACE#20FOR#20PERSONAL#20INFO>Last Name: </DOUBLE#20SPACE#20FOR#20PERSONAL#20INFO>
<DOUBLE#20SPACE#20FOR#20PERSONAL#20INFO> First Name: </DOUBLE#20SPACE#20FOR#20PERSONAL#20INFO>
<DOUBLE#20SPACE#20FOR#20PERSONAL#20INFO> Title/Rank: </DOUBLE#20SPACE#20FOR#20PERSONAL#20INFO>
<DOUBLE#20SPACE#20FOR#20PERSONAL#20INFO>College:  </DOUBLE#20SPACE#20FOR#20PERSONAL#20INFO>
<DOUBLE#20SPACE#20FOR#20PERSONAL#20INFO>Dept./Unit: </DOUBLE#20SPACE#20FOR#20PERSONAL#20INFO>
<DOUBLE#20SPACE#20FOR#20PERSONAL#20INFO> Appointment (%): </DOUBLE#20SPACE#20FOR#20PERSONAL#20INFO>
<Normal>University Contract Period (Check all that apply.  The University contract period includes evenings, 
weekends, and holidays during the term of employment.): </Normal>
<Normal>   </Normal>
<CHCKBOX#20INDENT#20HANGING>9 months  10 months  12 months  Summer </CHCKBOX#20INDENT#20HANGING>
<Normal> </Normal>
<Heading#202>PART I.  Conflict of Interest Screening </Heading#202>
<Normal>Please list and explain in an attached statement any &#8220;yes&#8221; responses.  Lists in Part II are not sufficient as an 
explanation. </Normal>
<Normal> </Normal>
<L><LI><Lbl>1.</Lbl>
<LBody></LBody>
</LI>
<LI><Lbl>2.</Lbl>
<LBody></LBody>
</LI>
<LI><Lbl>3.</Lbl>
<LBody></LBody>
</LI>
<LI><Lbl>4.</Lbl>
<LBody></LBody>
</LI>
</L>
<Normal> </Normal>
<Heading#202>PART II.  Listing of Non-University Income Producing Activities </Heading#202>
<L><LI><Lbl>&#61623;</Lbl>
<LBody></LBody>
</LI>
<LI><Lbl>&#61623;</Lbl>
<LBody></LBody>
</LI>
<LI><Lbl>&#61623;</Lbl>
<LBody></LBody>
</LI>
<LI><Lbl>&#61623;</Lbl>
<LBody></LBody>
</LI>
<LI><Lbl>&#61623;</Lbl>
<LBody></LBody>
</LI>
</L>
<Normal> </Normal>
<CHCKBOX#20INDENT#20HANGING>I HAVE NO ACTIVITIES THAT I AM REQUIRED TO REPORT. </CHCKBOX#20INDENT#20HANGING>
<Normal>Nature of your activities (see instructions for examples): </Normal>
<Normal> </Normal>
<Normal> </Normal>
<Normal> </Normal>
<Normal> </Normal>
<Normal>  </Normal>
<Normal>For whom (e.g. company/organization): </Normal>
<Normal> </Normal>
<Normal> </Normal>
<Normal> </Normal>
<Normal> </Normal>
<Normal> </Normal>
<Normal>Do you have an ownership interest in this company/organization? (If so, please explain in an attached 
statement.): </Normal>
<Normal> </Normal>
<Normal> </Normal>
<Normal> </Normal>
<Normal> </Normal>
<Normal> </Normal>
<Normal>  </Normal>
<Normal>2009-2010 Aug. 16 &#8211; Aug. 15 Retrospective Days spent during the reporting period: </Normal>
<Normal> </Normal>
<Normal> </Normal>
<Normal> </Normal>
<Normal> </Normal>
<Normal> </Normal>
<Normal>  </Normal>
<Normal>2010-2011 Aug. 16 &#8211; Aug. 15 Prospective Days to be spent in current reporting period: </Normal>
<Normal> </Normal>
<Normal> </Normal>
<Normal> </Normal>
<Normal> </Normal>
<Normal> </Normal>
<Normal> </Normal>
<Normal> </Normal>
<Heading#202>PART III. Affirmation </Heading#202>
<Normal>I affirm that I have read the University&#8217;s Policy on Conflicts of Commitment and Interes(available at: 
http://www.vpaa.illinois.edu/policies/conflict_toc.asp) and the above information is true to the best of my 
knowledge.  If significant changes in activities occur during the year, this form must be updated. </Normal>
<Normal> </Normal>
<Normal>Academic staff member&#8217;s signature:      Date: </Normal>
<Normal>  </Normal>
<Heading#201>Administrative Review and Approval, UIUC RNUA 2009-2010 </Heading#201>
<Normal>(Please complete the Conflict of Interest/Commitment Review AND Approval of Activities sections.  See 
instructions for Administrative Review and Approval regarding forwarding and retention of the Reports of 
Non-University Activities).  Deans/Directors should forward forms they receive and review to the Office of 
the Vice Chancellor for Research (or appropriate Vice President for UA Staff). </Normal>
<Normal> </Normal>
<Heading#202>PART IV.  Conflict of Interest/Commitment Review (Please attach a copy of any referenced 
explanation.) </Heading#202>
<Normal>A. Based on the activity reported and to the best of my knowledge and in my judgment: </Normal>
<CHCKBOX#20INDENT#20HANGING>No conflict of interest or commitment exists. </CHCKBOX#20INDENT#20HANGING>
<CHCKBOX#20INDENT#20HANGING>A conflict of interest or commitment may exist, but is being monitored by the department.  If so, 
please attach an explanation and forward to the next administrative level (Dean, Director, 
or Vice President). </CHCKBOX#20INDENT#20HANGING>
<CHCKBOX#20INDENT#20HANGING>A conflict of interest or commitment may exist that warrants further review.  If so, please attach an  
explanation and forward to the next administrative level (Dean, Director, or Vice 
President). </CHCKBOX#20INDENT#20HANGING>
<Normal>B.  Please complete if question 3 on page 1 of the form is answered affirmatively:  As described by the 
academic staff member, the involvement of University of Illinois students, faculty and/or staff in his/her 
non-University activities does not appear to be detrimental to those individuals. </Normal>
<CHCKBOX#20INDENT#20HANGING>Agree </CHCKBOX#20INDENT#20HANGING>
<CHCKBOX#20INDENT#20HANGING>Disagree  If so, please attach an explanation and forward to the next administrative level (Dean, 
Director, or Vice President). </CHCKBOX#20INDENT#20HANGING>
<Heading#202>PART V.  Approval of Activities (Please attach a copy of any referenced explanation.) </Heading#202>
<Normal>A.  Retrospective Activities (2009-2010) </Normal>
<CHCKBOX#20INDENT#20HANGING>No retrospective activities are reported or all retrospective activities are approved. </CHCKBOX#20INDENT#20HANGING>
<CHCKBOX#20INDENT#20HANGING>Some or all retrospective activities are not approved.  If so, please attach an explanation and 
forward to the next administrative level (Dean, Director, or Vice President). </CHCKBOX#20INDENT#20HANGING>
<Normal>B.  Prospective Activities (2010-2011) </Normal>
<CHCKBOX#20INDENT#20HANGING>No prospective activities are reported or all prospective activities are approved. </CHCKBOX#20INDENT#20HANGING>
<CHCKBOX#20INDENT#20HANGING>Some or all declared prospective activities are not approved.  If so, please attach an explanation 
and forward to the next administrative level (Dean, Director, or Vice President). </CHCKBOX#20INDENT#20HANGING>
<Normal>The above information is correct and complete to the best of my knowledge. </Normal>
<Normal> </Normal>
<Normal>U n i t H e a d S i g n a t u r e :       D a t e :    </Normal>
<Normal> </Normal>
<Heading#202>PART VI.  Review and Approval of Activities by Dean and Others as Required </Heading#202>
<Normal> </Normal>
<Normal>Dean/Director/VP Signature:      Date:    </Normal>
<Normal>(If approval needed.) </Normal>
<Normal> </Normal>
<Normal>Additional Reviews Signatures:      Date:    </Normal>
<Normal> </Normal>
<Normal>              D a t e : </Normal>
</Sect>
